Get in. Get out. Get even.
The Italian Job is a action, crime film directed by F. Gary Gray.
Charlie Croker pulled off the crime of a lifetime.
The one thing that he didn't plan on was being double-crossed.
Along with a drop-dead gorgeous safecracker, Croker and his team take off to re-steal the loot and end up in a
pulse-pounding, pedal-to-the-metal chase that careens up, down, above and below the streets of Los Angeles.
Charlie Croker, played by Mark Wahlberg.
Stella Bridger, played by Charlize Theron.
Steve, played by Edward Norton.
Lyle, played by Seth Green.
Handsome Rob, played by Jason Statham.
Left Ear, played by Yasiin Bey.
The Italian Job is a 2003 American heist action film directed by F.
Gary Gray and screenplay by Donna Powers and Wayne Powers.
The film stars an ensemble cast consisting of Mark Wahlberg, Charlize Theron, Edward
Norton, Jason Statham, Seth Green, Mos Def, and Donald Sutherland.
Inspired by the 1969 British film, but with an original story, the plot follows a motley crew of
thieves who plan to steal gold from a former associate who double-crossed them.
Despite the shared title, the plot and characters of this film differ from its source material; Gray described the film as "an homage to the original."
Most of the
film was shot on location in Venice and Los Angeles, where canals and streets, respectively, were temporarily shut down during principal photography.
Distributed by Paramount Pictures, The Italian Job was theatrically released in the
United States on May 30, 2003, and grossed over $176 million worldwide.
Critical response was generally positive, with publications comparing it favorably to the original
film while highlighting the action sequences, performances of the cast and humor.
A sequel, The Brazilian Job, was reportedly in development
in 2004, but was subsequently cancelled.
The film explores themes of gold, california, helicopter, hacker, venice, italy.
The tone is intense.